Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Ships and Shipping Records 1660-1943 MS 563
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
New-York Historical Society collection of ships and shipping records
1660-1943
MS 563
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
2.84 Linear feet in two document boxes, one oversize flat box, and one oversize folder
The collection includes a wide variety of documents compiled around a loosely-defined thematic connection to ships and shipping. Roughly 175 ships are represented in the collection, though often with just one document. Documents include bills of lading; invoices, receipts, account statements, and other financial papers; passes for ships; cargo manifests; depositions and other statements; sailing instructions and agreements; records of prizes won from captured ships; logbooks; crew lists; insurance policies; import certifications; and others. The collection also ranges widely over time, from a 1660-1663 journal (in Dutch) kept aboard the ships Golden Beaver and Golden Otter to a 1942 transcript concerning a fire aboard the S.S. Normandie at New York’s Pier 88.
New-York Historical Society.
Arrangement Note
The bulk of the collection is arranged in alphabetical order by name of ship. At the close of the collection are three folders with documents related to various ships. Two of these folders have a rough theme (Hudson River ships and import certifications). The third folder includes miscellaneous documents, which are itemized by ship in the container list.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers. Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition Note
The collection as a whole was compiled over time by New-York Historical Society from various donations and purchases, though the specific source is unknown for many of the items. When the source is known, it is noted at the folder level.
Scope and Contents Note
The collection, which was formed by New-York Historical Society over time from various donations and purchases, includes a wide variety of documents with a loosely-defined thematic connection to ships and shipping. Roughly 175 ships are represented in the collection, though often with just one document. Bills of lading and invoices, receipts, account statements, and other financial papers are most commonly found, though other documents include passes for ships; cargo manifests; depositions and other statements in connection with legal or other matters; sailing instructions and agreements; records of prizes won from captured ships; logbooks; crew lists; insurance policies; import certifications; and others.
The collection also ranges widely over time, from a 1660-1663 journal (in Dutch) kept aboard the ships Golden Beaver and Golden Otter to a 1942 transcript concerning a fire aboard the S.S. Normandie at New York’s Pier 88. Most documents, though, seem to date from the second half of the 1700s and the first half of the 1800s.
Despite the random nature of the collection and the lack of deep documentation for most ships, there are several folders that include particularly rich materials. These include, for example, the papers of the sloop Experiment (1785-1787), which document in detail the outfitting of the ship for a voyage from New York to Canton and back, along with payments to crew (portage bill), articles of association among its investors, and the eventual sale of the sloop and distribution of the proceeds. As another example, a folder includes the articles of association, stock certificates and other corporate documents concerning the Schuyler Steam Tow Boat Line and the Express Propeller Line (1847-1881). Although most ships are represented by only one or a few documents, these are often very rich documents, including an account of a British military expedition to the West Indies aboard the Boyne (1793-1794); signals to be used by the convoy of the Roman Emperor (1760s?); prize roll of the officers and seamen of the Constellation after the capture of the French frigate L'Insurgente (1799); logbook of the master of the Amphion on a voyage from New York to Montevideo (1820); the descriptive muster roll of the steamship General Grant (1864); morning reports of the prisoners in the brig of the St. Paul (1898); and orchestra programs and a captioned photograph of the band on the flagship Kentucky (1901-1904). Given the diverse nature of the materials in the collection, detailed scope notes are provided for each folder in the container list.
Bills of lading; Financial records; Invoices; Logbooks; Schooners; Shipping; Ships; Ships' manifests; Sloops; Steamboats
- Sloop Admiral Duncan. Oversize, 1803 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Scope and Contents note
  Proclamation by John Halkett, Esquire (Bahama Islands) that Sloop Admiral Duncan is fitted, armed and sent out upon a cruise against the King's enemies. (Gift from Gertrude Harrison, Elizabeth Harrison and William Harrison, 16 June 1936.)
- Ship Adriana, 1788-1793 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Invoices: Andrew Clow & Co., John Robertson, Sam Chubbard, Messrs. Rathbone & Benson, Ralph Pearson, Thomas Barlow, Thomas Porter, B. Gressham, Joseph Rider, Estate of Andrew Clow. Bills of Lading. Bills for boarding (Capt. Robertson of new Ship Adriana). Trademen's Bills. Account Statements of Andrew Clow & Co. Pay bearer, Captain John Robertson, Messrs. Rathbone & Benson. Advance to John Grant. Freight List. Discharge by David Cay, surviving partner of Andrew Clow & Co. (Gift of Diane R. Schneider, 4 June 1975.)
- Ship Albany, 1736-1743 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Receipts, Capt. James Clark. Agreement between Master James Clark and seamen, Voyage to Jamaica Bay, Hondorus, Amsterdam, New York. Order to sail, Capt. James Clark. Current account statement to Owners of Ship Albany. Sale of Ship Albany, Samuel Storke, proceeds. Memorandum re Ship Albany and Storke's breach of agreement. Henry Cuyler, Defense of 1/3 of the Ship Albany. Correspondence, Messrs. Cuyler & Livingston, Sam Storke, James Alexander (London), Daniel Crommelin (Amsterdam), Messrs. Widdow Albertus & John Hudshons, Charles Handly (New York)
- Revenue Cutter Alert, 1838 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Weekly abstract from the Journal of the U.S. Revenue Cutter Alert, Nicholas Bicka, Esq. Commander. (Gift from Robert Fridenburg, 1 July 1933.)
- Ship Alert. Oversize, 1812 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Ship Alert's Passport. Certificate that Ship Alert, Isaiah Eldridge, master, has no guns and may pass, owned by citizens of the United States. Contains presidential signature. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman, 22 November 1924.)
- Schooner Alert. Oversize, 1809 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Schooner Alert's Passport. Certificate that Schooner Alert, Alyn Muther, master, has four guns and may pass, owned by citizens of the United States. Contains presidential signature. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman, 24 January 1925.)
- Sloop America, 1813 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Bill of Lading. (Gift from C.K. Johnson, 14 December 1940.)
- Ship Amphion, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Logbook, Stephen Smith, Master. New York to Monte Video. (Gift of Mary C. Du Bois, 7 August 1933.)
- Sloop Anna Maria, 1817 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Invoice, Burnell Brown
- U.S. Steamer Arctic, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Abstract of Log of U.S.S. Arctic. Sounding across Telegraphic Plateau from Trinity Bay to S.C. of Ireland. (Gift of N.D., 1 December 1966.)
- U.S. Brig. Bainbridge, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Dimensions of sails. Outfits in the Gunners Dept., Boston.
- Ship Baltic, 1811 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Registration of Ship, Master James Eaken. (Gift from Charles F. Jenkins, 20 January 1926.)
- Brig. Beta, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Account of Mr. J.A. Cleveland; Sales of silks and teas received ex Brig Beta, Master W. Cleveland
- Sloop Betsy, 1783 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Policy of Insurance for Sloop Betsy, Master Abraham Gurling, Philadelphia. (Gift of Cyrus Curtis, 19 June 1875.)
- Ship Boyne, 1793 - 1794 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  List of the general, field, and staff officers of the Army in the West Indies, under General Sir Charles Grey, Journal commencing 19 November 1793 when Grey left London on the Boyne (logbook of conquest of Pigeon Island). (Gift from the estate of Augustus van Cortlandt van Rensselaer, care of Florence van Rensselaer, 8 June 1954.)
- Steamboat Bunker Hill, 1836 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Freight Bill
- Brig. Calliope, 1792 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Power of Attorney of Francis Anderson, cooper, to wife, Jane Anderson while aboard Brig Calliope, Captain Thomas Snell
- Ship Charles Carroll, 1831 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Bill of lading, Hottinquer & Co. (Gift from Harrold E. Gillingham, 18 January 1936.)
- Sloop Charming Peggy, 1770 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Certificate for a ship that gives Bond in the Plantations, and loads Rum or Spirits, not to land the same in the Isle of Man; Peregrine Van Emburgh, Master
- Armed Boat Chatham, 1776 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  John Christie's order to release James Wood from Work House
- Brig. Chauncey. Oversize, 1820 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Brig Chauncey's Passport. Certificate that Brig Chauncey, Richard Cok, master, has no guns and may pass, owned by citizens of the United States. Contains presidential signatures. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman, 22 November 1924.)
- S.S. Claribe, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Certificate of Discharge for Gardiner Stewart. (Gift of Mrs. Gardiner Stewart, February 1950.)
- Schooner Commerce, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Bills of lading, E.B. Clayton, Master Krag
- U.S.F. Constellation. Oversize, 1799 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Prize roll of the officers and seamen after the capture of the French Frigate L'Insurgente, February 09, 1799. Subscribers' Acknowledgement of prize money received of Henry Bainbridge by hand of Charles Biddle for the French Frigate L'Insurgente. Purser's receipt of prize money for French Frigate L'Insurgente. Assignments of annexed certificate (assignments of prize money)
- U.S.F. Constellation, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Correspondence of G.A. Denniston to mother describing a confrontation witt the native inhabitants of Ceicer de Mer in the South China Sea. (Gift of Marie Will through the Chicago Historical Society, 15 November 1986.)
- U.S.F. Constitution, 1814 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Receipt Book - N2, William M. Hunter
- Sloop Content, 1694 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Certificate of the Collector & Receiver of the Province of New York re rum import (broke) and condemnation of sloop
- Schooner Convention, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  License of vessel, Captain Roe Haviland. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman, 26 November 1923.)
- Galley Cornwall. Oversize, 1759 (Drawer Oversize - Medium, Folder -)
  Articles of Agreement between James Laroche (on behalf of owners) and David Ducumb (Captain) for 2nd Voyage to windward and gold coast, Africa; Crew List
- Schooner Decatur, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Protest of Master Jonathan T. Morrill. (Purchased from Irving Levy, 23 April 1936.)
- Sloop Dolphin, 1791 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Manifest of cargo bound for New York, James Hinsdale, Master. (Gift from Charles F. Jenkins, 1 May 1925.)
- Ship Dorset. Oversize, 1738 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Warrant of Survey, Samuel Winterburn, Commander. (Gift of the American Numismatic Society, 27 May 1941.)
- Dutch Ships: Golden Beaver, Golden Otter, 1660-1663 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Journal kept aboard the Ship Golden Beaver and Ship Golden Otter from the Manhattan to Patria and the return to the Manhattans (in Dutch, with English translation provided by Professor Kenneth Scott.)
- Schooner Eliza, 1803 - 1804 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Agreement of voyage and wages, Master Anior Harker, voyage from Newbern, NC to New York and return. Agreement of voyage and wages, Master Mathias Attinson, voyage to Jamaica and return.
- Schooner Emily, 1811 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Bill of lading, William W. Woodward, Philadelphia, Master Nathan Foster. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman (purchased from library of William P. Clyde)?, 20 May 1931.)
- BK. Emita, 1898 - 1904 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Wharfage fee, Standard Oil Co. of NY (Devoe Works), Master E.H. Praz. Wharfage Fees, James D. Leary, Master W.E. Reemi.
- Schooner Expert, 1718 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Expert's Cargo. Peter Henick's Memorandum of Protest and Notes.
- Sloop Experiment, 1785 - 1787 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Voyage From New York to Canton, China, and back. Invoices: Henry Sheafe, William Nixson, Robert Dale, Stewart & Jones, Thomas Browne, Thomas Barry, Thomas Biggs, William Kippin, J. Shipprey, Alexander Robertson & Co., Stewart Dean, Peter Schermerhorn, William Bradford, Elias Nexsen, Jacob Vanderheyden, John Bogert, Joseph Shurtleff, Abraham Brincherhoff, Jacob Gerhart, David Holly, Joseph Rose, Isaac Jones, Glen & Bleeker, William Lowther, James Carter, Abraham Willson & Isaac Brincherhoff, Elias Kip, Richard Clark, George Warner, John Whelton, Joshua Jones. First Cost & Outfit of the Sloop Experiment - S. Dean Master. Articles of Agreement between Owners of the Sloop Experiment. Memorandum as to distribution of shares of Sloop Experiment. General account and final settlement of the Sloop Experiment. Disbursements. Bill of Sale of Sloop Experiment. Sales of the Sloop Experiment. Transaction at a meeting of the owners of Sloop Experiment. Sales at auction of Edward Laight and William Deasoil. Receipt of William Laight & Co the respective sums and all demands against Sloop Experiment, Master Stewart Dean. Agreement of voyage. Instruction from Owners to Captain Stewart Dean. Portage bill, including list of ship's crew (including an African-American), with wages advanced and due. Wharfage fees. Account statements. Cooper and carpenters' accounts. (Gift of Edward W. Laight, 10 April 1838. Edward was the son of William Laight, a stockholder and agent for the concern.)
- Ship Fair American, 1799 - 1806 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Account Sales (damaged on voyage from Charleston); Hamburg, John C. Brevoor, Master.
- U.S. Schooner Ferret, 1824 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  List of Articles required by Commander D.G. Farragut, Esq.
- Ship Florida. Oversize, 1823 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Ship Florida's Passport. Certificate that Ship Florida (of New York), James Wilson, master, has one gun and may pass, owned by citizens of the United States. Contains presidential signature. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman, 22 November 1924.)
- Brig. Forest. Oversize, 1825 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Brig Forest's Passport. Certificate that Brig Forest (of New York), Henry Greenleaf, master, has one gun and may pass, owned by citizens of the United States. Contains presidential signature. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman, 22 November 1924.)
- Ship Fortitude. Oversize, 1803 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Articles of Agreement between Hezekiah Pinkham, Master, and seamen; Crew list; Voyage from New York, Norfolk, ports in Europe, and return
- U.S. Steamer General Grant. Oversize, 1864 (Drawer Oversize - Medium, Folder -)
  Complete Descriptive Muster Roll of the Crew of the U.S. Steamer General Grant. (Purchased from C.K. Johnson, from the Naval History Fund, 15 November 1938.)
- Ship General Thomas, Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Names (and shares received) of Officers and Men on Board the General Thomas at the taking of the Schooner Eliza, John Hodge, Commander; at the taking of the Sloop Lark, Jonathan Laurence, Master; at the taking of the Sloop Black (?), John Farley, Master; at the taking of the Snow Hopewell; at the taking of the Sloop Success; at the taking of the Sloop Nancy
- Ship Gideon Barstow. Oversize, 1832 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Ship Gideon Barstow's Passport. Certificate that Ship Gideon Barstow (of Rochester), N.C. Cary, master, has no guns and may pass, owned by citizens of the United States. Contains presidential signature. (Gift from Stuyvesant F. Morris, 3 March 1921.)
- Horseboat Golden Fleece, 1818 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  Blot Mem and Calculations Book
- H.M.S. Greyhound, 1722 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Depositions of Aron Bogaert, of Henry Kip, and of William Boll concerning an affray and breach of the peace.
- Schooner Hamilton. Oversize, 1807 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  The Crew List of Schooner Hamilton, John Richards, Master for voyage bound for La Vera Cruz. (Purchased, with the Naval History Fund, 22 December 1944.)
- Sloop Harriet, 1800 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Order of Recorder to sell Sloop Harriet. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman, 6 April 1927.)
- Sloop Hera, 1806 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Correspondence/Bill of Lading of Collins and Perkins to Dr. Jedidiah Morse of Charlestown regarding a delivery of two bundles of books. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman (purchased from library of William P. Clyde)?, 20 May 1931.)
- Ship Hostor(?), 1698? (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Scope and Contents Note
  Statement by surveyor Hungerford providing information against the ship.
- Sloop Huntress, 1813 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Sloop Industry, 1795 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Manifest of Inward voyage to New Bedford, Elizar Hathaway, Master. (Gift of Cornelius von Erden Mitchell, 13 May 1940.)
- Schooner James, 1812 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Depositions of James Nevers and of Mark Leighton relative to Schooner James
- Ship James Cropper, 1822 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Petition of Passengers on board James Cropper bound for New York from Liverpool regarding quieting of bell. (Gift from Gertrude Harrison, Elizabeth Harrison and William Harrison, 16 June 1936.)
- Brig. James Wells, 1809 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Depositions of Eliphabet Kingsbury and Abraham Cummings regarding vessel leaking. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman, 28 March 1923.)
- Brig. Jerome. Oversize, 1824 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Brig Jerome's Passport. Certificate that Brig Jerome (of New York),George W. Lee, master, has no guns and may pass, owned by citizens of the United States. Contains Presidential signature. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman, 22 November 1924.)
- U.S. Flagship Kentucky, 1901-1904 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Orchestra Programs on voyages; some contain menu on reverse side. 1902 photograph of U.S.F.S Kentucky band at morning colors, noting names and instruments played. (From the E.B. Child collection, February 1946.)
- Sloop Lark, 1796 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Manifest of Cargo on board Sloop Lark, Master Chris Godfrey, bound from Providence to New York. (Gift from Charles F. Jenkins, 20 January 1926.)
- Ship Liberty, 1803 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Receipts and other documents relating to Ship Liberty's business in France (many of the documents are in French). (Gift from A.E. Rueff, 26 May 1928.)
- Schooner Lonsdale, 1803 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Bill of Lading. (Gift of Thomas Ollive Mabbott, 8 May 1942.)
- Cartel Schooner Lucy, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  List of Cabin Passengers and Servants and their Stores for Schooner Lucy, Absolam Savage, Master; List of Stores for Schooner Lucy; List of Stores of Mr. Robert Abbott and of Mr. Jasper Howe; Permission request for provisions for animals in stores.
- Schooner Mail, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Bill of Lading. (Gift from Thomas Ollive Mabbott, 24 June 1938.)
- Sloop Marey, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Ship Martha, Oversize, 1811 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Ship Martha's Passport. Certificate that Ship Martha (of New York), Laban Gardner, master, has no guns and may pass, owned by citizens of the United States. Contains Presidential signature. (Purchase, 15 November 1938.)
- Schooner Mary Ann, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Certificate of Landing; Schooner Mary Ann, Master Joseph Tompkins.
- Sloop Mary and Elizabeth, 1704 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Statement in the Suit over the Sale of Sloop Mary and Elizabeth by George Parker to William Griffiths. (Purchase)
- Sloop Matilda, 1804 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Entry of merchandize exported by John Speyer on board Sloop Matilda, John Dodge, Master, for the Coast of Africa.
- Ship Milford, 1789 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Return of Ship Milford, Captain Shaw from Newfoundland. (Gift from Charles F. Jenkins, 1 May 1925.)
- Brig. Minerva, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Receipt of Captain Hilburn; Crew List
- Schooner N.W. Smith, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Certification of the Port of Charleston that no Slave or person held to Service or Labor is concealed on board Schooner N.W. Smith, E.N. Smith, Master. (Gift from Clarence L. Lersner, 8 December 1944.)
- Ship Nancy, 1769 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Bill of Lading; Ship Nancy, John Waddle, Master.
- Schooner Nathaniel Chase. Oversize, 1861 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Crew List of Schooner Nathaniel Chase, David Doane, Master. (Gift from Chales F. Heartman, 6 July 1946.)
- Clipper Ship Neptune's Favorite, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Bill of Lading for Clipper Ship Neptune's Favorite, Master Emmertin. (Gift from William A. Robbins, 14 May 1941.)
- Schooner New England, 1830 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Clearance Certificate of the Port of Wilmington, NC for Schooner New England, Hiram Cutts, Master, bound for Havana. (Purchased from Charles F. Heartman, 19 May 1931.)
- Prize Ship New Hampshire. Oversize, 1746 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Record of Capture of French Ship, Le Heron (now, New Hampshire), William Burt, Master, by English Ship Maremaid, Capt. Warwick Calmadge.
- Ship New Harliquin, 1762 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Account of Joseph Forman.
- Ship New York Packet. Oversize, 1810 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Ship New York Packet's Passport. Certificate that Ship New York Packet (of New York), Timothy Clifton, master, has no guns and may pass, owned by citizens of the United States. Contains Presidential signature. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman, 24 January 1925.)
- S.S. Normandie, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Transcript in the Matter of Five-Alarm Fire in the S.S. Normandie at Pier 88, North River, Manhattan, February 9, 1942 at 2:49 p.m. Before Thomas P. Brophy, Chief Fire Marshall -- Witness Testimony.
- Ship Ocean. Oversize, 1809 (Box Oversize - Small, Folder -)
  Ship Ocean's Passport. Certificate that Ship Ocean (of New York), Samuel Eaken, master, has no guns and may pass, owned by citizens of the United States. Contains Presidential signature. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman, 19 December 1923.)
- Sloop Olive, 1760 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Insurance Policy for Sloop Olive, Master Edgerton on voyage from Surinham (Suriname) to New York or New London.
- Schooner Orders in Council, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Journal of the Order in Council (A Letter of Marque, Privateer), John Howard, Master; Crew List.
- Steamboat Oregon, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Correspondence of John H. Cornish to wife, Martha (c/o Col. Joseph E. Jenkins), describing traveling on the boat on the Hudson River.
- Bark Osprey, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Outfitting book of Bark Osprey, Reuben W. Crop, master. (Gift of Katherine R. Rogers, 28 June 1955.)
- Ship Pacific, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Passengers' Thank you note to Captain Stanton on their voyage from Liverpool to New York; Passenger List.
- Sloop Patience, 1768 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Sundries Receipt for Sloop Patience, William Ward, Master.
- Steamship Philadelphia, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Marine Protest, Case of the Steamship Philadelphia, Master Findlay Schenck, on a voyage from New Orleans to New York.
- Steamboat Pittston, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Inspector's Certificate of Steamboat Pittston, William Murry, Master. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman, 11 February 1925.)
- Frigate Raby, 1705 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  Notice of Frigate Raby's voyage to Lisbon and her Majesty's Plantations and return when not detained by embargoes. (Gift from Samuel V. Hoffman, 16 October 1923.)
- Brig. Ranger. Oversize, 1831 (Drawer Oversize - Medium, Folder -)
  [Ottoman Turkish] Clearance of Brig Ranger and Captain Eldridge at Constantinople (in Arabic?).
- Schooner Regulator, 1799, 1807 (Box 2, Folder 28)